<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Lim&#39;s Stuff</title>
  <subtitle>Human</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://limdauto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-04-22T16:16:32.000Z</updated>
  <id>https://limdauto.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lim H. &lt;limdauto@gmail.com&gt;</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The triplicity of modern life</title>
    <link href="https://limdauto.github.io/2017-04-22-triplicity/"/>
    <id>https://limdauto.github.io/2017-04-22-triplicity/</id>
    <published>2017-04-22T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-04-22T16:16:32.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Or why I don’t have a Facebook account and tend to delete my blog once every couple of years.</p>
<a id="more"></a>
<p>I have an interesting habit. Once every few years I throw away an online presence and recreate a new one. I don’t do it intentionally; it just sort of happens. When people ask why I don’t have an active Facebook account, I have never been able to articulate the exact reason until recently when I watched a movie called <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt5247022/" target="_blank" rel="external">Patterson</a>. The movie brilliantly potrays the duality of life in Patterson through a clever twins metaphor and, more subtly, through the stark contrast between a character’s public life and her private one: a bus driver and a poet; a housewife, an artist and a cupcake entrepreneur; a lonely, rejected man too consumed in publicly acting out his self-fulfilling pessimistic fantasy; and a rapper wannabe trapped in a dirty laundromat. All of them interweave into a rich texture making up the town’s seemlingly boring life. Yet the movie doesn’t completely resonate with me, as my perception of modern life isn’t so much a duet as it is a triplet. Somewhere between our private and public lives resides an online presence, semi-public and psuedo-personal. It contributes as much to our well-being as having a stable job and filling a notebook with beautiful poems. </p>
<p>Think about what happens when you post a Facebook status. And no, I don’t mean it the way they do in a software development interview where you need to chart out the path between your fingertips and Facebook data center. I mean think about whom you represent and to whom you address. Are you posting something that you are equally willing to broadcast to the neighborhood with a microphone? Or are you posting something so intimate that you normally only share with the closest of friends? If it’s a public persona you are representing, are you ready to accept whatever feedback from the nameless, faceless crowd that you address? If it’s a private, heartfelt message, does it hurt if no one replies? These questions tend to confuse me more than it enlightens, so I skip the entire platform altogether; I can’t decide whom I want to be on Facebook. Or Twitter for that matter.</p>
<p>It’s a rather similar deal with blogging. My blog is usually a mix of technical, professional and personal thoughts. It tends to stay on the private side, containing stuff I’d usually share with a close friend over a pint of beer. But once in a while, I’d look at it and realize I don’t recognize the person I am portraying anymore, so I’d throw it away and start fresh, just like Patterson starting over with his poems after Marvin tore the old notebook to shreds. His poems usually don’t have a point, neither does my blog. It’s just a natural extension of who I am, both incomplete and evolving. And what I have here is its next incarnation.</p>
<p>As a final note, I’d like to talk a bit about blogging software. The previous incarnation of my blog witnessed my infatuation phase with Haskell and therefore was setup using <a href="https://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hakyll</a>. As much as I love Haskell, static generators written in dynamic languages tend to have a richer ecosystem due to a lower barrier to entry, so I get a wider range of plugins, themes and tutorials. It’s similar to some of the arguments made in [The Rise of Worse is Better][<a href="https://www.jwz.org/doc/worse-is-better.html" target="_blank" rel="external">https://www.jwz.org/doc/worse-is-better.html</a>]. That said, I’m using <a href="hexo.io">Hexo</a> for this version of my blog and it’s very good.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Or why I don’t have a Facebook account and tend to delete my blog once every couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="life" scheme="https://limdauto.github.io/categories/life/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
